Preliminary Inventory to the Mark Starr Papers TAM.019
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Mark Starr Papers
1912-1980s
1930-1960
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Starr, Mark, 1894-1985
Starr, Helen Norton
TAM.019
37.5 Linear Feet (48 boxes)
Mark Starr (1894-1985), was the education director of the International Ladies Garment Workers Union (1935-1960) and a longtime activist in civic and political affairs, including as an officer and candidate of the Liberal Party. As head of the ILGWU Education Department, he supervised a program that established compulsory educational requirements for candidates for union office, and was president of the American Federation of Teachers. Workers Education Local 189, and served on governmental commissions and boards of civic organizations, including Americans for Democratic Action, the League for Industrial Democracy, the American Labor Party. This unprocessed collection contains correspondence, manuscripts, clippings, printed ephemera and subject files. The majority focus on Starr's activities outside his official capacity as ILGWU Educational Director, and illuminate educational enterprises he associated with, such as: U.S. Advisory Commission on Educational Exchange (the Fulbright program), the U.S. Information Service, New York City Community College, the Ford Foundation, the Georgia Workers Education Service, Harvard Fellowships for union members, a Labor Extension Service Bill for workers' con¬tinuing education, labor education programs abroad, and the United States Works Progress Administrations Workers' Education Project. Other materials relate to political groups he associated with, including: Americans for Democratic Action, the League for Industrial Democracy, the American Labor Party, and the Liberal Party. One box of material on Japan describes post war labor developments and U.S. interest in trade unionism there, and there is also correspondence from a tour of Far East.
Box 1-45
Arrangement
The collection is organized into two unprocessed series: Accession I, (boxes 1-16), folder level control; Accession II, (boxes 17-45), box level control.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Scope and Contents note
This unprocessed collection contains correspondence, manuscripts, clippings, printed ephemera and subject files. Although these primarily to Starr's activities outside his official capacity as ILGWU Educational Director, many focus on his unflagging interest in adult and workers education. Letters and documents illuminate educational enterprises he associated with, such as: U.S. Advisory Commission on Educational Exchange (the Fulbright program), the U.S. Information Service, New York City Community College, the Ford Foundation, the Georgia Workers Education Service, Harvard Fellowships for union members, a Labor Extension Service Bill for workers' con¬tinuing education, labor education programs abroad, and the United States Works Progress Administrations Workers' Education Project. Correspondence, memoranda, and clippings document attacks on and response of Public Affairs Committee, publishers of educational pamphlets, to McCarthyist attacks by Friends of Democracy in the early 1950's. Drafts of several PAC pamphlets are included.
Some correspondence and documents relate to political groups he associated with at various times, including: Americans for Democratic Action (1942-1959), the League for Industrial Democracy (1944-1958), the American Labor Party (1940-1944), the Liberal Party (1944-1957). One box of material on Japan describes post war labor developments and U.S. interest in trade unionism there; one report describes meeting with Douglass McArthur, whom Starr found impressive. There is also correspondence from 1965 tour of Far East. Manuscripts of published material includes drafts of educational material and pamphlets, and manuscripts for approximately eighty unpublished items, including college essays, and eleven book reviews.
Historical/Biographical Note
Mark Starr (1894-1985), was the education director of the International Ladies Garment Workers Union (1935-1960) and a longtime activist in political and civic affairs. Mr. Starr was the chairman of the Liberal Party in Queens from 1945 to 1959 and was the Liberal candidate for the House of Representatives for the district covering western Queens in 1962. As head of the ILGWU Education Department, he supervised a program that offered 600 classes a year in the United States and Canada, established compulsory educational requirements for candidates for union office,with courses offered in trade unionism and related fields. He was president of the American Federation of Teachers. Workers Education Local 189 (during the 1940s), and served on numerous governmental commissions and boards of directors of civic organizations.
Mr. Starr, a native of Somersetshire, England, started work at age 13 as a hod carrier. He began his teaching career with the miners in Wales, ran unsuccessfully as a Labor candidate for Parliament and entered this country in 1928. Mr. Starr was the center of a brief but intense public controversy in 1943, when Mayor Fiorello H. La Guardia nominated him to be the city's first director of adult education. Mr. Starr was the only one of 100 candidates found qualified by a screening committee, but he was rejected by the Board of Education, with the chairman later saying that Mr. Starr was disqualified by his "long record as a labor protagonist."
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Mark Starr in 1983; an additional accession was donated in 1985 by his wife, Helen Starr. The accession number associated with these gifts is 1988.002.
Labor unions and international relations |z United States; Labor unions -- United States.; Labor movement -- United States.; Clippings (information artifacts); Working class -- Education.; Manuscripts; Working class |x Education |z United States.; Correspondence.; Labor unions |x Officials and employees |z United States.; Labor movement |z Japan.; Starr, Mark, 1894-1985; Starr, Helen Norton; American Federation of Teachers. Workers Education Local 189; League for Industrial Democracy; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; American Labor Party; United States. Works Progress Administration. Workers' Education Project; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Educational Dept.; Americans for Democratic Action; Public Affairs Committee
- First Accession, I; 460012
  - Americans for Democratic Action (Correspondence, Clippings, Notes on Conference), 1949-1952; 460135 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Assembly, 1950-1959; 460134 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bibliographies, Study Suggestions for ILGWU, 1952-1959; 460133 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Civil Service Commission, 1954-1959; 460132 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Commission [United States Advisory Commission on Educational Exchange] (Correspondence, evaluations, Clippings), 1948-1952; 460131 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Commission [United States Advisory Commission on Educational Exchange] (minutes, Correspondence, Clippings, Conference Outlines), 1953-1959; 460130 (Box 2, Folder 1-7)
  - Community College: N.Y.C. (budget plans, board of trustees' meetings, Clippings, Correspondence, minutes, petitions, program planning), 1955-1959; 460129 (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
  - Council for the Advancement of Secondary Education (Correspondence), 1954-1959; 460128 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Credit Unions (Correspondence, report forms, overviews, articles), 1940-1958; 460127 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Farm Labor (Correspondence, press releases), 1953-1959; 460126 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Fascism (press releases, Outlines); "Fascist Words and Fascist Deeds" essay by M. Starr, 1930's; 460125 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Film Council of America (Correspondence, program of annual meeting), 1951-1952; 460123 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Ford Foundation, Fund for Adult Education (Correspondence, statements), 1948-1952; 460122 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Free Enterprise (Clippings, Manuscripts, press releases, reports, speeches), 1947-1959; 460121 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Georgia Workers Education Service (Correspondence, Conference Outlines), 1947-1950; 460120 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Harvard Fellowships (application, Correspondence, memos, press releases, recipients), 1942-1943; 460119 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Harvard Fellowships (application, Correspondence, memos, press releases, recipients), 1944-1946; 460118 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Harvard Fellowships (application, Correspondence, memos, press releases, recipients), 1947-1948; 460117 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Hudson Shore Labor School, 1946-1951; 460116 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Labor Extension (Correspondence, reports), 1945-1947; 460115 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Labor Extension (Correspondence, reports), 1946-1950; 460114 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Labor Textbooks, Educational Material (Correspondence), 1942-1943; 460113 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Labor Theatre Committee, Touring the "Steel" (Correspondence, minutes), 1937; 460112 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - List of Books for Lagos Library, 1966; 460111 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - League of Industrial Democracy (Correspondence, press releases), 1948-1955; 460110 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - League of Industrial Democracy (Correspondence, press releases), 1956-1957; 460109 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - League of Industrial Democracy (Correspondence, press releases), 1958-1959, 1967; 460108 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Marshall-Plan (Statements by Public Affairs Committee, Foreign Relations, Department of Agriculture, Notes for Radio Broadcasts), 1947-1949; 460107 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Mayor's Advisory Council (Correspondence, reports), 1954-1957; 460106 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Mergers (Clippings, Manuscripts), 1929-1932; 460105 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Metropolitan Education Television Association (Correspondence, Clippings), 1954-1961; 460104 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - National Conference on Christians and Jews (Correspondence), 1948-1959; 460103 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - National Recovery Act: Coal, 1933; 460102 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - New York Stock Exchange, 1957-1958; 460101 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Old Age (General Correspondence, Clippings, event: Little White House Conference on Aging, Manuscripts include: "Positive Heath of Older People"; "Jobs After Forty"; "Making the Most of Maturity"), 1955-1958; 460100 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Public Affairs Committee: Correspondence, memos, reports, board meetings, Manuscripts; Japanese Relocation Problems; "Friends of Democracy Controversy": report written by FOD on Maxwell S. Stuart; Health Issues, 1950-1958; 460136 (Box 7, Folder 1-7)
  - Public Affairs Committee: Correspondence, memos, reports, board meetings, annual meetings, Manuscripts, PAC history, 1958-1973; 460094 (Box 8, Folder 1-5)
  - Public Speaking, 1941; 460092 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Radio: Clippings, press releases, scripts, talks, Manuscripts on the radio; Canadian Broadcasting Corporation, Columbia Broadcasting System, The I.L.G.W.U. Quiz, Station SCFL (Chicago), Station WNYC, Station WEVD, Public Service Radio Institute (University of Wisconsin), CBS West Coast, Station WGVA, Station WQQW, Station WMCA, Station WNBC, N. J. State CIO Council: "Listen to Labor", Ted Hudes Radio Productions, 1936-1951; 460091 (Box 8, Folder 7-12)
  - Slogans, 1936-1938; 460088 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Southern Summer School for Workers (Correspondence), 1939-1947; 460087 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA), 1956-1958; 460086 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - The Town Hall, Inc. (Correspondence, The Town Hall Dinner Outlines, "Town Meeting" radio show, 1937-1951; 460085 (Box 9, Folder 4-5)
  - Transport Workers Union (TWU), 1937-1956; 460084 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - TV-Radio (Metropolitan Television Association, Radio Free Europe, WNYC), 1951-1954; 460083 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Veteran Soldiers, 1945-1946; 460082 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - USSR (Correspondence, minutes, Manuscripts, Institute for the Study of the USSR Documents), 1944-1959; 460081 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - War and Peace, 1946-1957; 460080 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Wellesley Summer Institutes (Correspondence, promotional Material), 1936-1946; 460079 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Women's Trade Union League (educational programs, Correspondence), 1935-1959; 460078 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Workers Education (Correspondence, manuscript, memos, reports), 1939-1959; 460077 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Workers Education Bureau, 1942; 460076 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Workers Education: Ford Adult Education Fund Progress Report, 1951; 460075 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Workers Education: General Correspondence, 1930-1959; 460074 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Workers Education: ILGWU Correspondence, 1945-1959; 460073 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Workers Education: New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, 1945-1948; 460072 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Workers Education: New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations (Correspondence), 1944-1959; 460071 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Workers Education: Reports on Tanganyika and Singapore, 1961-1962; 460070 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Workers Education: "The University's Role in Workers' Education", undated; 460069 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Workers Service Program, 1939; 460068 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Workers Service Program (Conference Outlines, project descriptions), 1940; 460067 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Workers Service Program, 1941; 460066 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Workers Service Program (Correspondence), 1942; 460065 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Workers Service Program, 1943; 460064 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Workers Service Program Clippings, 1942; 460063 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Workers Education Conference: Annual Washington's Birthday, 1937-1957; 460062 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Workers Travel Association, 1936-1951; 460061 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Workmen's Circle (Correspondence), 1940-1948; 460060 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - World Federation (Correspondence), 1942-1950; 460059 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - World Federation (United World Federalists, International Conference of Free Trade Unions), 1949-1950; 460058 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Youth (Youth Board, Youth Builders, Pioneer Youth, World Assembly of Youth, Youth of All Nations), 1943-1952; 460057 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Board of Education (Correspondence), 1940-1941; 460056 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Dewey, John (manuscript by and on J.D.), undated, 1949; 460055 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - College Essays Written By Mark Starr, undated, 1916-1921; 460054 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Local 189 (Correspondence), 1952-1957; 460053 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Association of Catholic Trade Unions (Correspondence, Clippings), 1940-1941; 460052 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Published Articles (Clippings), 1939-1954; 460051 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Unpublished Manuscripts: Book Reviews, undated, 1958-1959; 460050 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Unpublished Manuscripts: No Titles (On Politics), undated, 1958; 460049 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Unpublished Manuscripts: No Titles (On Trade Unions), undated, 1945, 1953; 460048 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Unpublished Manuscripts: A-C, undated, 1938-1950; 460047 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Unpublished Manuscripts: D-F, undated, 1937-1955; 460046 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Unpublished Manuscripts: G-L, undated, 1940-1957; 460045 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Unpublished Manuscripts: Moral Standards in Business and Labor, 1953; 460044 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Unpublished Manuscripts: M-O, undated; 460043 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Unpublished Manuscripts On Social Services in Britain, undated; 460042 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Unpublished Manuscripts: P-S, undated, 1937-1959; 460041 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Unpublished Manuscripts: T-W, undated, 1940-1952; 460040 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Intellectual Freedom, Teachers' Rights (Correspondence, Manuscripts), 1937-1940; 460039 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1935-1939; 460038 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Miscellaneous, 1934-1958; 460037 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Socialist Party, Correspondence, 1936-1953; 460036 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Letters To Westbrook Pegler And Other TV Critics, 1939-1943; 460035 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Presidents Committee on Education Beyond The High School, Middle States region, 1957; 460034 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - White House Conference on Education, Washington, D.C., 1955; 460033 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Notes on Britain, 1943-1945; 460032 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Notes by Mark Starr, undated, 1943, 1957; 460031 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - American Labor Party (A.L.P.): Correspondence, Manuscripts, undated, 1941-1944; 460030 (Box 13, Folder 16-Oct)
  - Liberal Party: Correspondence, 1944-1948; 460029 (Box 13, Folder 17-22)
  - Liberal Party (Campaign Materials, Clippings, Correspondence, Press Release, Statements), undated, 1941-1952; 460028 (Box 14, Folder 14-Jan)
  - Japan (Clippings; Correspondence; eye witness accounts of American visitors; labor Materials; Manuscripts and articles on trade union activities, workers education; pamphlets, statistics accounts), 1945-1966; 460027 (Box 15)
  - A.U.B.T.W. Education Outlines, 1920s; 460026 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Aberdare District Miners Federation: Economic Classes, 1916; 460025 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Central Labour College League, undated; 460024 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - International Federation of Trade Unions, 1921, 1926; 460023 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Labour College: meeting of Governors, minutes, 1923; 460022 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - National Council of Labour Colleges (NCLC), undated, 1918-1927; 460021 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Ruskin College, 1927; 460020 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Scottish Labour College Committee, undated; 460019 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Workers Educational Association, 1928; 460018 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Industrial Combination in England, Summary of (by P. Fitzgerald), 1927; 460017 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Clippings on Business, Trusts and Banks, 1927-1928; 460016 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Clippings on Labor Education, 1917-1928; 460015 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Clippings on Russia, 1921-1927; 460014 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1924, 1973; 460013 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Postcards, 1929 (Box 16, Folder 15)
- Second Accession, II; 459982
  - M. Starr: General Correspondence, Manuscripts; League of Industrial Democracy: Correspondence, fliers, memos, minutes of board meetings, project plans, statements; International Labor Office: Correspondence, minutes, statements; Eugene V. Debs Foundation: Correspondence, meeting minutes, announcements; Socialism and the Socialist Party: manuscript: Socialist Manifesto and Program by Erich Fromm, workers education programs; Local 189: Clippings, constitution, Correspondence, labor education Related Materials, meeting minutes, undated, 1937, 1960-1975; 1960-1975; 1960-1975; 1960s; 1960s; 460011 (Box 17)
  - Conference on Science, Philosophy, and Religion organized by The Institute on Ethics, The Institute for Religious and Social Studies, and The Jewish Theological Seminary of America: papers, discussions, program Outlines; Communism: Clippings, Correspondence; Clippings (originally named as "Diary Documents"); Conference, convention badges, 1956; 1951-1954; 1930s-1950s; 460010 (Box 18)
  - Articles on Ireland; British Labor Movement; General Correspondence; I.L.G.W.U. Documents; L.I.D.: Labor Poems; Clippings, Labor Related; Labor Unions in Action, 1920s; 1920s-1930s; 1940s-1950s; 1950s; 1930s; 1940s-1960s; undated; 460009 (Box 19)
  - CIO and Labor Related Clippings, Correspondence; Personal Manuscripts; Social Illiteracy (Clippings, Correspondence, Manuscripts); Miscellaneous Correspondence; Women Question; Free Enterprise; Psychology and Philosophy (Clippings); Work Conditions ("Outlines for the Course in Union Methods" by Horace Bryan); Manuscripts: Labor and Corruption, Anti-Semitism, Jews in the Labor Movement; General Clippings; General Correspondence; Miscellaneous Documents, 1945, 1950s; 1930s; 1950s; 1970s-1980s; 1950s; 1950s; 1920s; 1938; 1950s; 1960-1962; 1960-1962; 1960-1962; 460008 (Box 20)
  - Miscellaneous Documents, Clippings, Notes; Union constitutions; Supervisor Exams; Immigration (Clippings, Correspondence, miscellaneous Documents); General Correspondence; Labor Songs; Educational General Reports; Travel Notes, 1950s-1970s; 1920s-1930s; 1930s; 1950s; 1950s-1970s; 1950s; 1942-1944; 1930s; 460007 (Box 21)
  - Vocational Education (Correspondence, Clippings, Manuscripts); Workers Education: General Articles; Workers Education: General Correspondence; Workers Education: Documents, Manuscripts; AFL-CIO Clippings; Labor in America: Correspondence, 1930s-1940s; 1940s; 1940s; 1940s-1950s; 1956; 1940s-1950s; 460006 (Box 22)
  - Consumerism; Books Offered for Sale; Brookwood Labor College: British Labor Movement Course, Clippings, Correspondence, reports, miscellaneous Documents; Labor Education Material (Local 189); Labor: General Clippings, Correspondence, Documents, Manuscripts; I.L.G.W.U.: Entertainment Materials, songs, events; I.L.G.W.U. Manuscripts: "History of the I.LG.W.U. 1900-1938", "Settling Prices In Dresses", "Where Does America Go From Here?", 1920s-1930s; 1960s-1970s; 1930s; 1960s; 1920s-1950s; 1940s; 1930s; 460005 (Box 23)
  - Personal Correspondence; Personal Documents; Clippings, Correspondence and miscellaneous Documents of:; Rubber Workers; New York Joint Committee; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; State, County and Municipal Workers of America; Federated Labor Schools; Workers Education; Steel Workers Organizing Committee; John Dewey Society, 1935-1949; 460004 (Box 24)
  - Clippings: General; Japan: Clippings, Correspondence, and Other Related Material; Esperanto: Clippings, Correspondence, and Other Related Material, 1920s-1940s; 1940s-1950s; 1950-1951; 460003 (Box 25)
  - Clippings; Peace: Clippings, Correspondence and Other Related Materials; Starr, Mark: personal Correspondence; Educational Commission; Election '62: Clippings, Correspondence, speech Notes and Other Related Documents; Handwritten Notes and articles, 1920s-1940s, 1963; 1963-1965; 1937-1939; 1952; 1962; 1920s-1930s; 460002 (Box 26)
  - Correspondence: M. Starr; Great Britain: Trade Union Congress, Labor, Workers Education (Clippings); Liberal Party; Unions: United Automobile Workers, Hat Workers, Caterers, Textile Workers, Women's Union, United Mine Workers, United Electrical and Radio Workers; Workers Education Committee and Bureau; Education Aid Materials (Outlines, syllabuses, overviews); Literature; Clippings, 1943-1968; 1930-1939; 1950-1966; 1936-1944;; 1941-1941; 1920-1933; 1930-1946; 460001 (Box 27)
  - The Wannamaker Diaries; Personal Documents (Correspondence, Conference and Event Notes, fliers, diary Notes); Wimbledon Elections (Clippings, Notes); Diary books, 1932, 1933; 1918-1932; 1923-1924; 1912-1929; 460000 (Box 28)
  - Clippings; Miscellaneous Manuscripts, Notes; LGWU: Press Releases; Queens Liberal Party; Television and Radio (Correspondence, Misc. Documents), 1942-1943; undated, 1943-1961; 1943; 1956-1957; 1959; 459999 (Box 29)
  - Trade Union Institute and Research; Trade Union Congress; LGUW - Health Issues; "Facing Facts"; Miscellaneous Documents; Clippings: Imperial Conference; Clippings: General; Clippings: Labor; Occupational Safety and Health Act; Local 189, AFT; Brookwood Workers College: Clippings, Correspondence (of Helen Norton and Josephine Colby), Syllabuses, class Outlines); Labor Journalism, 1966; 1966; 1924-1943; 1938; 1932-1933; 1920s, 1930s; 1958-1959; 1973; 1972; 1922-1933; 1931-1934; 459998 (Box 30)
  - United Nations (Clippings, Documents); Industrial Unionism; Berger, Sam: Manuscripts on Labor and Peace; Meany, George: Testimony Before the Committee of Education and Labor (senate); Second Corning Conference; Clippings; Correspondence; Brookwood; Meany, George: Testimony Before the Committee of Education and Labor; South Africa Apartheid; League for Industrial Democracy, 1970-1971; 1936-1937; 1939; 1959; 1961; 1930s; 1942-1943; 1920s; 1958; 1968; 1960s-1970s; 459997 (Box 31)